parity.io 2019-04-30

# Privacy Policy | Parity Technologies

Parity Technologies Limited ( **“We”** ; **“us”** ; or **“our”** ) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our terms of use on our websites [parity.io](https://parity.io/), [paritytech.io](https://paritytech.io/), [polkadot.io](https://polkadot.io/) and any subdomains such as [sub0.parity.io](https://sub0.parity.io/) (the **“Sites“** ) and any other documents referred to on them) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.

### What data do we collect from you?

The Ethereum client written in the programming language Rust known as Parity does not collect information from you, however any information you publish onto a blockchain like Ethereum is public by design.

If you go to our Sites or utilise other services, we may collect and process the following personal data about you:

  * **Information you give us.** This is information about you that you give us by filling in forms on our Sites, filling in forms on the sites of third party vendors providing us with a service, or by speaking with us in person, corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. It includes information you provide when you agree to our contributors license agreement ( **“CLA”** ), apply to attend one of the events that we host, attend one of the events that we host, apply for a job on our Sites, ask to receive our newsletter, ask to receive notifications about jobs in the Substrate ecosystem, provide us with feedback on Parity's tech and when you report a problem with our Sites. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number and job application information (e.g. your CV, education data, and picture).
  * **Information we collect about you.** With regard to each of your visits to our Sites we may automatically collect the following information: 
    * technical information, including the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, browser type and version, and versions, operating system and platform; and
    * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL), page response times and download errors.
  * **Information we receive from other sources.** This is information we receive about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide or, to the extent permitted by law, publicly accessible information about you on e.g. business social media. We are working closely with third parties (including, for example, recruitment services providers, and event organisation service providers and event partners). We will notify you when we receive information about you from them and the purposes for which we intend to use that information.

### Cookies

Our Sites uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our Sites. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our Sites and also allows us to improve our Sites. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our **“Cookie Policy”** below.

### For what purposes do we use your data and what is the legal basis for this use?

We may use information held about you in the following ways and relying on the following legal bases:

  * As required by Parity to conduct our business and pursue our legitimate interests, in particular: 
    * to notify you about changes to our service;
    * to ensure that content from our Sites are presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
    * to administer our Sites and for internal operations, including troubleshooting and statistical purposes;
    * to improve our Sites to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
    * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
    * as part of our efforts to keep our Sites safe and secure;
    * to use information you provide to investigate any complaints received from you or from others, about our Sites or our products or services;
    * to address any interest you or your team show in Parity’s tech, Polkadot or any collaboration with us;
    * to provide you with information about jobs in the Substrate ecosystem;
    * to improve Parity's tech;
    * to assess your eligibility for the particular role you applied for;
    * to assess your eligibility for any role that we might have available;
    * to schedule, arrange and administer events and meetups in which you have expressed an interest (including creating an attendance record for the event and sending anonymised data to the venue including attendees, dietary requirements and accessibility requirements);
    * to document the copyright and other rights granted with contributions made under our CLA;
    * to use data in connection with legal claims, compliance, regulatory and investigative purposes as necessary (including disclosure of such information in connection with legal process or litigation); and
    * Information we receive from other sources: We will combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We will use this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).
  * Where you give us consent: 
    * we or our carefully selected partners will send you direct marketing in relation to our relevant products and services, or other products and services provided by us, our affiliates and carefully selected partners. However, we will only provide you with marketing related information after you have, where legally required to do so, opted in to receive those communications and having provided the opportunity for you to opt out at any time.
    * we place cookies and use similar technologies in accordance with our Cookies Policy and the information provided to you when those technologies are used
    * on other occasions where we ask you for consent. We will use the data for the purpose which we explain at that time.
  * For purposes which are required by law: 
    * In response to requests by government or law enforcement authorities conducting an investigation.

### Relying on our legitimate interests

We have carried out balancing tests for all the data processing we carry out on the basis of our legitimate interests, which we have described above. You can obtain information on any of our balancing tests by contacting us using the details set out later in this notice.

### Withdrawing consent or otherwise objecting to direct marketing

Wherever we rely on your consent, you will always be able to withdraw that consent, although we may have other legal grounds for processing your data for other purposes, such as those set out above. In some cases, we are able to send you direct marketing without your consent, where we rely on our legitimate interests. Once we have received notification that you have withdrawn your consent, we will no longer process your information for the purpose(s) to which you originally consented unless there is no other legal ground for the processing.

You have an absolute right to opt-out of direct marketing, or profiling we carry out for direct marketing, at any time. You can do this by following the instructions in the communication where this is an electronic message, or by contacting us using the details set out below.

### Who will we share your data with, where and when?

We will share your personal information with:

  * Any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries for : 
    * website maintenance and security; and
    * recruitment and hiring.
  * Selected third parties including but not limited to: 
    * business partners and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with them or you;
    * our newsletter service provider for the purposes of providing you with our newsletter;
    * event organisation service providers for the purposes of scheduling and arranging events and meetups in which you have expressed an interest;
    * our applicant tracking system service provider for the purposes of assessing your application for a role at Parity;
    * third party developers for and/or providers of website hosting and maintenance; and
    * the Web 3 Foundation for the purposes of assisting and/or following up with you, and coordinating that assistance/follow-up where you have shown interest in Polkadot and/or Substrate.

We will also disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * In the event that we sell or buy any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal data to the prospective seller or buyer of such business or assets.
  * If Parity Technologies Limited or substantially all of its assets are acquired by a third party, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Parity Technologies Limited, our customers, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area ( **"EEA"** ). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA (in our case the US) who works for us or for one of our suppliers.

Where information is transferred outside the EEA, and where this is to a stakeholder or vendor in a country that is not subject to an adequacy decision by the EU Commission, data is adequately protected by EU Commission approved standard contractual clauses, an appropriate Privacy Shield certification or a vendor's Processor Binding Corporate Rules. A copy of the relevant mechanism can be provided for your review on request to [admin@parity.io](mailto:admin@parity.io).

Our Sites may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks, and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies. Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Your rights

You have the right to **ask us for a copy** of your personal data; to **correct** , **delete** or **restrict** (stop any active) processing of your personal data; and to **obtain the personal data you provide to us for a contract or with your consent in a structured, machine readable format** , and to ask us to **share (port) this data to another controller**.

In addition, you can **object to the processing** of your personal data in some circumstances (in particular, where we don’t have to process the data to meet a contractual or other legal requirement).

These **rights may be limited** , for example if fulfilling your request would reveal personal data about another person, where they would infringe the rights of a third party (including our rights) or if you ask us to delete information which we are required by law to keep or have compelling legitimate interests in keeping. Relevant exemptions are included in the GDPR. We will inform you of relevant exemptions we rely upon when responding to any request you make.

To exercise any of these rights, or to obtain other information, such as a copy of a legitimate interests balancing test, you can get in touch with us using the details set out under the Section **“Contact”** below. If you have unresolved concerns, you have the **right to complain** to an EU data protection authority where you live, work or where you believe a breach may have occurred.

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data. You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at [admin@parity.io](mailto:admin@parity.io).

### Which entity is my data controller, and which affiliates might my data be shared with?

The data controller for your information is Parity Technologies Limited of c/o IGNITION LAW Moray House, Floor 1, Moray House, 23-31 Great Titchfield Street, London, United Kingdom, WC1W 7PA.

Your data might be shared with our group company Parity Technologies Deutschland GmbH, Glogauer Str. 6, 10999, Berlin, Germany for recruiting purposes and for the management of group functions.

### How long will you retain my data?

Where you are a contributor, customer or a registered user, we will keep your information for the duration of any contractual relationship you have with us, and, to the extent permitted, after the end of that relationship for as long as necessary to perform the purposes set out in this notice.

Where we process personal data with your consent, we process the data until you ask us to stop and for a short period after this (to allow us to implement your requests). We also keep a record of the fact that you have asked us not to process your data indefinitely so that we can respect your request in future.

For data about your visits to our Sites and where we process personal data for Sites security purposes, we will retain this data for 12 months following your last visit of our Sites.

Data you provided to us in the course of your job application, or so as to be informed about jobs in the Substrate ecosystem will be kept for 6 months, if your application was not successful. If you enter into an employment relationship with us, the relevant information will be kept for the duration of the employment contract as part of your personnel file.

Laws may require us to hold certain information for specific periods. In other cases, we may retain data for an appropriate period after any relationship with you ends to protect itself from legal claims, or to administer its business.

### How you protect my data

We strive to maintain the highest standards of security and Parity has put in place robust technical and organizational measures for the protection of your data in accordance with the current, general state of the art technologies, especially to protect the data against loss, falsification or access by unauthorized third persons. However the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. So, whilst we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our Sites. Any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your personal data we will use strict procedures and security features to prevent unauthorized access.

Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our Sites, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

### Cookie-Policy

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by the websites that you visit. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. The use of cookies is now standard for most websites. If you are uncomfortable with the use of cookies, you can manage and control them through your browser, including removing cookies by deleting them from your ‘browser history’ (cache) when you leave the site. See the subsection **“How to manage cookies”** for further information.

### Necessary cookies

The law states that we can store cookies on your device if they are strictly necessary for the operation of this site. To set all other types of cookies we need your permission. Necessary cookies help make a website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies.

### Parity Technologies’ use of cookies

The only cookie set on Parity Technologies’ websites is the `__cfduid` cookie. This cookie is set by a third party, CloudFlare (a content delivery network service), and is necessary for the website to function properly as it is used to identify trusted web traffic. It does not correspond to any user ID in the web application, nor does the cookie store any personally identifiable information. In addition, it’s a “first-party” cookie bound to Parity’s hostname and not accessible from anywhere else, which makes it unusable for tracking purposes. Where technically possible it is also marked as “Secure” which would only allow its transmission over encrypted channels. <https://support.cloudflare.com/hc/en-us/articles/200170156-What-does-the-CloudFlare-cfduid-cookie-do->

This cookie expires after 1 year.

### How to manage cookies

Current versions of web browsers offer enhanced user controls regarding the placement and duration of both first and third party cookies. Search for "cookies" under your web browser's “Help menu” for more information on cookie management features available to you. You can enable or disable cookies by modifying the settings in your browser. You can also find out how to do this, and find more information on cookies at [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). However, if you choose to disable cookies in your browser, you may be unable to complete certain activities on our Sites or to correctly access certain parts of it. If you would like more information about interest-based advertising, including how to opt-out of these cookies, please visit [youronlinechoices.eu](http://youronlinechoices.eu/).

### Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

* * *

### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to [admin@parity.io](mailto:admin@parity.io) or by writing to Parity Technologies Limited of c/o IGNITION LAW Moray House, Floor 1, Moray House, 23-31 Great Titchfield Street, London, United Kingdom, WC1W 7PA.

* * *

"We", "our", "Parity" – refers to Parity Technologies Limited.

This notice supplements our Privacy Notice and describes how we collect, use, share and retain additional personal data collected when you participate in a Parity event (whether as an attendee, guest, or speaker), and how to access and control this additional data. Please let us know if you have any questions about this supplemental notice.

### What additional data do we collect from you:

**Event registration**

When you register to participate in a Parity event we will collect some or all of the following information from you directly or we will receive it from Eventbrite or Meetup:

  * Name
  * Meetup or Eventbrite profile link
  * Organisation
  * Email address
  * Dietary requirements
  * Accessibility requirements

When you book an event through Eventbrite or Meetup you will also have to agree to their terms and conditions of service. Please note that Eventbrite and Meetup are third-party services that are not owned or managed by Parity. This policy only refers to the way Parity will use your information.

If you wish to attend one of our events but do not wish to use Eventbrite or Meetup to book a place, please contact the event organiser. Contact details for each event are provided on the event booking page.

**Event photography and audio / video recordings**

We frequently take photos and record audio and/or video at our events. If so, we may make and store photographs containing your likeness and recordings of your voice and likeness. We may associate your image and the sound of your voice with your name if you are identified during the recording or identify yourself by name.

If you do not want your photograph to be taken or to be featured in video or audio of an event please let a member of our team know.

### What we do with this additional data and why:

**Event registration data**

We may use this information for the purposes of scheduling, organising and administering the event, this includes but is not limited to:

  * registering you to attend the event;
  * sending you an email to you to confirm your registration and provide you with updates regarding the event;
  * tracking and administering dietary and accessibility requirements; and
  * organising and arranging an appropriate venue and refreshments.

**Event photography and audio or video recordings**

We may use, edit, copy, exhibit, publish, or distribute photos and audio or video recording from our events for the purposes of promoting our events and Parity.

### When we share this additional data

**Event registration data**

Unless otherwise stated we use Meetup or Eventbrite to manage online registration for our events. We may share your personal data with Meetup or Eventbrite (or an alternative service provider), event partners (including but not limited to: event space providers, caterers and security service providers) and partner organisations (for example partners with whom we are joint hosting or presenting) as needed to provide you with information and services associated with the event and so as to administer the event itself.

**Event photography and audio or video recordings**

We may publish our or distribute photos and audio or video recording from our events via social media, including Twitter, Telegram, and LinkedIn. In doing so we will share those photos, audio or video with those services and their users.

### How long do we retain your data?

**Event Registration Data**

If you have informed us that you wish to be contacted about future events we will keep your data until you tell us that you no longer wish to be contacted. We will check from time to time that you still wish to hear from us. If you have informed us that you do not wish to be contacted about events we will delete your information within eight weeks of the event.

**Event photography and audio or video recordings**

Any photos and audio or video recording from our events that we choose not to use for the purposes of promoting our events and Parity will be deleted within eight weeks of the event.

We keep this policy under regular review and we will post any updates on this webpage.

* * *

### How to contact us

Please contact us at [admin@parity.io](mailto:admin@parity.io) if you have any questions about this supplemental policy or the information we hold about you.

* * *

## Statutory information

Statutory information about Parity Technologies Limited:

  * Registered in England and Wales
  * Registered Number: 09760015
  * Registered Office: Ignition Law, Moray House Floor 1, 23-31 Great Titchfield Street, London, United Kingdom, WC1W 7PA.
